<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-02-26T22:26:47+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Nick This Week</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Where To Play Catan Online</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/02/20/Where-To-Play-Catan-Online.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Where To Play Catan Online" /><published>2023-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/02/20/Where%20To%20Play%20Catan%20Online</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/02/20/Where-To-Play-Catan-Online.html">&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;video-embed.css&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been living in Mexico for the past 5 months. I started in La Paz, met a girl, and followed her to Monterrey for the holidays. Around Christmas time we had some of her friends over to my Airbnb to hang out and play Catan. I belive this was the second time I had ever played Catan. A few years ago I played with my roomates, but it was my first time and the tutorial I received left a lot to be desired. All I remembered was ports are important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time, still with little instruction, and even though we didn’t finish the game, I had fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was actually a lot of fun. Like most board gaems it requires atleast 4 players. I was chomping at the bit to play again, but its not always easy to organize a group of 3 other people for a game night. Especially if you are living in a foreign country…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if I can’t get my fix in person, what should I do? The internet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;where-can-i-play-catan-online&quot;&gt;Where Can I Play Catan Online?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a little bit of searching I came across &lt;a href=&quot;https://colonist.io/&quot;&gt;Colonist.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like Colonist because they have both a mobile and web app and you can play against bots and people. One of the draw backs of playing Catan in real life is that the game takes forever! Literally it can take hours to complete a game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I typically play agains bots when I play on Colonist. I like this becasue I can rep games, and I can complete a game in 15-20 minutes, rather then 2ish hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-am-still-a-newbyhow-can-i-learn-to-play-catan-better&quot;&gt;I am still a Newby…How can I learn to Play Catan Better?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a big fan of Youtube. I “Cut the Cord” years ago, and I primarily watch Youtube these days. So when I wanted to figure out how to play Catan better I went to Youtube first. After some searching I found a channel I really like, its this guy named &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@DyLightedPlaysCatan&quot;&gt;Dylighted&lt;/a&gt; and I highly recommend his channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to check out one of his videos I recommend this one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dylighted-playing-catan-on-colonistio&quot;&gt;Dylighted Playing Catan on Colonist.io&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;!-- Feel free to change the width and height to your desired video size. --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/P3EhcOT4JyA&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>itsnickkane</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/01/31/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2023-01-31T00:11:11+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-31T00:11:11+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/01/31/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/01/31/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll requires blog post files to be named according to the following format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YEAR-MONTH-DAY-title.MARKUP&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YEAR&lt;/code&gt; is a four-digit number, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MONTH&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DAY&lt;/code&gt; are both two-digit numbers, and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MARKUP&lt;/code&gt; is the file extension representing the format used in the file. After that, include the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&apos;Tom&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &apos;Hi, Tom&apos; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the base Jekyll theme. You can find out more info about customizing your Jekyll theme, as well as basic Jekyll usage documentation at &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;jekyllrb.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the source code for Minima at GitHub:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll&quot;&gt;jekyll&lt;/a&gt; /
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/minima&quot;&gt;minima&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the source code for Jekyll at GitHub:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll&quot;&gt;jekyll&lt;/a&gt; /
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;jekyll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Downside of Creating an LLC</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/12/16/The-Downside-of-Creating-An-LLC.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Downside of Creating an LLC" /><published>2022-12-16T00:11:11+00:00</published><updated>2022-12-16T00:11:11+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/12/16/The%20Downside%20of%20Creating%20An%20LLC</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/12/16/The-Downside-of-Creating-An-LLC.html">&lt;p&gt;It is nearly the end of 2022 and I have hopefully just completed the last step in dissolving the California Limited Liability Company (LLC) I established in 2015. In all honesty, the process was not that painful. However, when you combine ignorance, neglect, and unpaid taxes, it became an albatross that I am ready to be done with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2015, I had dreams of starting the next billion dollar software unicorn. I had an idea for a real estate software start up that I imagined would become the new way in which residential real estate would be bought and sold around the world. Keep in mind, I am not a software developer, I had never built software, and wasn’t even that computer literate…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got my real estate license when I was 19 years old and sold residential real estate to family and friends while I attended undergrad. After I graduated I moved to San Francisco and began selling software. At the time I was selling Applicant Tracking Systems (ATS). ATS software is software to help with recruiting, either for agencies or companies doing in house hiring. To me it appeared that the recruiting process and the home buying process were very similar. A job is like a house, the hiring entity is like the seller and the purchaser is like the job seeker. With this insight, I thought I could build software that functioned similar to an ATS but for Real Estate and dis-intermediate the agent allowing buyers and sellers to connect directly via software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is probably worth diving into my mistakes and what I learned, but that is for another time. Ultimately, the start up was unsuccessful and I moved on in 2018. I moved on, notice I didn’t say, “successfully dissolved the legal entity”. I guess I should take a step back first. Around the same time that I decided to build said software, and start the business I thought it would be a good idea to set up a legal entity. Although, it is advised that you consult with an Attorney, CPA, etc., I went the DIY route. I visited the California Secretary of State website, did a little reading, downloaded the 1-page Articles of Organization, filled it out, mailed it in, and viola! I was in business. Well not quite business - I had theoretically shielded myself from personal liability, but I also signed myself up for an additional $800 minimum annual tax that was due to the California Franchise Tax Board (FTB) each year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With my shiny new legal entity in hand I was able to open a bank account, get an Employer Identification Number (EIN), and little else. An EIN is essentially a Social Security Number for a business. I never had any employees, only independent contracts so it was less complicated legally, and at that time I was primarily just spending money on developing the Web App.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When tax time came, TurboTax was my go to. I had been using TurboTax for years to successfully file and pay my personal taxes, and now that I had a single member pass through LLC I figured no reason to change. I upgraded and paid for the “Professional” version and was guided through the entire process to ultimately file and pay electronically. In fact it was extremely easy, as it turns out too easy… I am not intending to disparage TurboTax, I still use them to prepare my personal taxes and I think it is an incredible product. The mistakes are my own. As it turns out, TurboTax did a great job guiding me through the business tax preparation process and even provided a complete and easy to download PDF version of my completed tax returns. However, they did not transmit and pay electronically the California FTB as I had naively believed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the requirements for maintaining an LLC in California is to file a Statement of Information every two years with the Secretary of State. All said, this is an extremely easy process, there is even an online portal in which you can search, file, and pay in less that 5 minutes. In order to maintain my LLC, I would file the statement of information every two years and go on my way. Since I had ceased my start up aspirations in 2018 and had re-entered the labor force, my intention was to close out my LLC by filing a Certification of Cancellation instead of my usual Statement of Information. At the end of 2020 when I attempted to cancel, to my surprise, I was unable. When I accessed the online portal there was a notice that my LLC was suspended by the FTB. Not realizing what the message meant, I googled around and realized that the FTB was the “Franchise Tax Board”. As you can imagine, at this point my heart sunk. This was the start of my nearly two year ordeal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first attempted to login to the online FTB portal to view my account, see what my potential outstanding balance was, and see if I could resolve it myself online. This attempt was unsuccessful. Accessing the portal required information that I did not have or could not recall at the time, and the error messages were nondescript. Thus, I reached a dead end. The next step was to call. During my call with an agent I was able to pinpoint my previous issue, the missing piece of information was the address on file. Unfortunately, from 2015 and 2020 I had moved 4 times and recalling all of the complete addresses was difficult. In the end, the address I had on file was a now defunct co-working space, fortunately I had some old emails with the leasing agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After gaining access to my account, I was informed that I did not have an outstanding balance. YES! What a relief. Well…as it turns out there was no outstanding balance because I had never properly filed returns with the FTB. It’s not that I didn’t owe, they just didn’t know how much yet. To the credit of all the people I interacted with at the FTB, they were extremely knowledgeable, professional, and courteous. To say the least I felt like a scumbag. I’m being alerted that I haven’t paid the proper taxes in approx. 7 years and my excuse is, “Oh, I thought I was…” even though this was true, I still felt like an imbecile. To their credit, It never felt like they were being condescending or rude, the exact opposite in fact. It felt more like they were on my side, alerting me of all the potential options and what I needed to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To set the stage, my LLC currently had no assets, no bank account, no debt, nothing. For all intents and purposes the last year of operations was 2017. I never had any investors or employees, I self funded the venture with savings and some personal debt (i.e credit cards, personal loan) that had since been paid off. The first option I pursued was to file a Request for Voluntary Administrative Cancellation - Form 3716. From my conversations I thought this might be a long shot, as the first question and one of the main requirements for consideration was answering “No” to the following questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Was the domestic LLC ever doing business (that is, actively engaged in any transaction for the purpose of financial, pecuniary gain, or profit)?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other requirements had to do with having any current assets or debts, so I figured it was possible depending on their definition/ interpretation of doing business. For 2015 - 2017 my “doing business” was strictly limited to expenses, so I thought I had a shot. It turns out this disqualified me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I received the written notice that I was not eligible for the Administrative Cancellation, I got back on the phone with the FTB. This time, I was told of a program that might work, the Offer In Compromise - Form 4095 BE. In order to explore this option I first needed to file my missing returns. Fortunately, I actually had been completing them in TurboTax each year and all I needed to do now was simply find the saved PDF versions, print them out, and fax them in. So, that is what I did. I located the Limited Liability Company Return of Income - Form 568, and faxed them to the FTB with my completed Offer in Compromise. At this time I did not know what my exact liability would be, but I was able to estimate it over the phone with the FTB agent, so I had a decent idea of what it would be. Yes, the past due balances do accrue interest. The amount I owed was close to $8,000, this is significantly more than the $5,600 that you get by multiplying $800 a year by 7 years. With this number in hand, I crafted an offer based on what I could feasibly pay in one lump sum, as that is what was required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After approximately three months, I received a voicemail from the FTB that they had received my Offer in Compromise and wanted to discuss my eligibility for the program. We ultimately settled on an amount, it was higher than my initial offer, but still significantly less then the total outstanding. From my understanding this was primarily based on ability to pay, likely hood of the FTB collecting more in a reasonable amount of time, and my desire to dissolve/cancel the LLC with the California Secretary of State after the FTB had removed the suspension. With this understanding reached, I obtained a cashiers check and mailed it to the FTB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I was not guaranteed that this amount would close out my account (it still needed to be reviewed and signed off on by management), I was hopeful that my LLC ordeal was coming to an end. Nearly 45 days later, I received a letter in the mail stating that my offer had been accepted. With my letter in hand completed and mailed to the CA Secretary of State the Certificate of Cancellation - LLC 4/7.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">It is nearly the end of 2022 and I have hopefully just completed the last step in dissolving the California Limited Liability Company (LLC) I established in 2015. In all honesty, the process was not that painful. However, when you combine ignorance, neglect, and unpaid taxes, it became an albatross that I am ready to be done with.</summary></entry></feed>